is timu just one big scam and is it a
legit company and is it safe to buy from
temu now with prices as low as three
dollars for a pair of bluetooth
headphones or six dollars for a pair of
running shoes you're probably wondering
whether these prices are just too good
to be true and as with anything in life
when something sounds too good to be
true or if the prices are just too low
there's always a catch now as with any
Online Marketplace there are potential
risks to be aware of such as slow
shipping times poor customer service and
issues with product quality now in this
team of review I'm going to explore the
pros and cons of shopping on timu
explain how to place and cancel orders
and initiate returns and also explain
whether Teemu is a safe and legitimate
online shopping platform so first off
what is Teemu well Teemu is a us-based
Online Marketplace that offers low
prices on thousands of products shipped
directly from China now the company is a
subsidiary of PDD Holdings which is a
Chinese company and since their launch
timu has been making headlines in the
e-commerce World partly due to a Super
Ball commercial that led to a sharp
increase in app downloads now Teemu
provides access to a wide range of
affordable products that are made in
China and because products are shipped
directly from China Chinese vendors
avoid the expense of storing inventory
in the U.S resulting in lower prices for
customers now overall Teemu is a direct
competitor to AliExpress offering
extremely low prices for cheap items
made in China and in fact I would argue
that timu is just a poor man's version
of AliExpress with Superior marketing
now the app started in September of 2022
and is now the number one most
downloaded free app in the Apple Store
and the reason why they've grown so fast
is because they are practically throwing
money at people if you can convince your
friends to join you receive credits for
free stuff and influencers are heavily
incentivized to promote the app now as a
YouTuber in this space I have literally
received an email from their team twice
a week in just the last month offering
to pay me money to make a YouTube video
and no I did not accept any payment for
this video but I say this to warn you
all that you can't trust anyone who is
actively promoting this app right now
because chances are it's a paid
promotion for free stuff
Teemo is literally hemorrhaging money
right now to create buzz in the
marketplace and it's working by the way
if you're enjoying this video so far
make sure you sign up for my free six
day mini course below
now the million dollar question is is
timu legit well timu is a legitimate
Online Marketplace that is owned by pin
duo duo which is a publicly traded
company on the NASDAQ Stock Exchange now
timu currently has a rating of three out
of five on trustpilot and 3.7 out of 5
on site jabber and if you look closely
at their customer reviews you'll notice
a significant number of complaints from
users about late delivery incorrect
sizing and counterfeit items now to
limit your chances of a negative
experience with Teemu stick to
internationally known Chinese Brands
such as Lenovo Huawei and xiaomi now
while Teemu is a legitimate e-commerce
platform always use caution and read
product reviews before purchasing now is
it safe to buy from temu buying from
timu is safe because the company offers
a purchase protection program that
protects buyers in case of damaged goods
or fraud now the timu purchase
protection program covers items that
don't match the listing description
items that arrive damaged and items that
are lost in the mail here's how the
program works you initiate a return by
selecting the items you would like to
return on the your orders page and then
you just click on the return button
after selecting the return method and
indicating the reason for your return
you just print the return label and ship
the package via USPS or UPS if your
order is eligible for the purchase
protection program you will be refunding
your money in addition to the purchase
protection program temu also provides an
estimated processing and shipping time
and then once your order is shipped you
receive a tracking number
now what is their return policy exactly
tmu's return policy allows you to return
eligible items within 90 days from the
data purchase but you must return the
item physically within 14 days of
submitting your return request to
qualify for a refund now tmu's return
window is longer than competitors like
AliExpress shine and wish they even
offer free return shipping labels for
your first return within the 90-day
window you can return additional items
from the same order as long as the
90-day window has not expired but there
is a 7.99 shipping fee which is deducted
from your refund
timu processes refunds within three
working days after receiving the return
package from the customer
refund amounts which are applied to the
customer's account can take seven to
Thirty business days depending on the
payment method for example credit card
payments can take up to 18 business days
to process now if you choose tmu credit
balance as your refund method you
actually receive your refund amount
within a couple of minutes I think this
strategy is brilliant because if you
read the reviews it can take an
extremely long time to get a cash refund
but you can get stored credit instantly
which encouraged you to get another
product
now does timu offer free shipping and
how long does it actually take to ship
something Teemu offers free shipping on
almost all orders with standard shipping
and standard shipping usually takes 7 to
15 business days to arrive now if you
need your order sooner you can choose
express shipping which is free for
orders above 129 bucks or 12.90 for
orders below that amount now once your
order has been confirmed you will see
the estimated delivery time and shipping
cost on your confirmation page the
warehouse can take up to one to three
days to process your order and you'll
receive a message once your order has
been shipped okay so that's their
official policy in reality if you look
at reviews on sitejabber and trustpilot
there have been many cases of
undelivered packages mysterious charges
incorrect orders and unresponsive
customer service here's a very recent
review from someone who left an eloquent
review with a ton of upvotes don't get
fooled by the advertisements of buy 100
and get a 20 coupon to be issued upon
items shipped you will never get it
you'll speak with an untrained 24 7
customer service rep that cannot solve
any of your issues timu lures you into
their site with low prices shipments
arrive in plastic bags poorly packaged
half damaged and for returns they
calculate in a way that they will still
make some money out of it and in this
review this person provided a tip for
consumers beware of promised coupons
upon shipment you will never get them
keep screenshots of the final purchase
cart before you click purchase they will
come up with all sorts of excuses so you
cannot redeem your coupon and they have
very cheap plastic bags used for
packaging poor handling will damage
fragile goods and they have Shady return
and refund policies total scam
here's another negative review that I
picked up I purchased 60 worth of items
last night got 20 off and free shipping
it turned out that they charged me 12.90
for shipping I chatted with two online
customer support reps it was an awful
experience neither of them were willing
to help and it would take 15 minutes
before they responded or they just tried
to brush me off now I can't even cancel
the order and then finally this review
is literally posted five minutes ago
before I clicked record on this video
Teemo is going downhill they are not
shipping orders I have had five orders
pending since the last week I spent
hours in chat and on the phone they
don't care and aren't honest at all one
person made a promise to me that my
orders would ship the next day it didn't
now they don't promise a thing someone
should have thought the Super Bowl ad
thing through a bit more that's when
they started going downhill and customer
service totally sucks they are not
shipping orders save your money no one
really needs a junk and crap and stuff
that they sell okay so those are just
some negative reviews that I've picked
up off the internet and to be fair let's
look at a positive review
I'm new to timu but I'm already so
impressed with all the things they do
for their customers like free shipping
with no minimum spend is already so
surreal but the fact that they have a
90-day free return policy and give you
credit for late delivery other online
shopping places could never team is also
the first place I've seen that actually
broadcast their efforts to not
contribute to global warming which is
always a huge Plus for me efforts to not
contribute to global warming I had to
chuckle while reading this review now
I'm not going to say that it's fake but
my radar definitely went off anyway
while I would take these reviews with a
grain of salt you should buy from temu
with the proper expectations timu is not
a scam and it's a legit company but do
not expect high quality Goods if you see
wireless bluetooth headphones for three
bucks and free shipping do you really
think that it's going to be a quality
product
likewise I probably wouldn't run on a
pair of running shoes for six bucks from
an unknown brand
just like AliExpress all these products
are coming from China with little or no
quality control the main difference is
that Teemu is doing a fantastic job of
marketing themselves with their cheap
products and they are paying big
influencers off to leave positive views
of their company it really is a
brilliant strategy and it's working so
well that the timu app is number one
as I mentioned before Teemu is a poor
man's AliExpress with great marketing
now you guys are probably wondering how
do you get free products from temu
here's a fun fact most new customers
actually aren't paying any money at all
teemu's referral program on social media
has been working like gangbusters
because people love free stuff and all
team we want right now is app downloads
to receive free products in temu you
must refer others to sign up for the
Teemu app and the more referrals you
make the more credit you earn that can
be applied to free items in team news
referral program has allowed the app to
spread quickly because influencers and
users promote the app to get the free
stuff and I'm willing to bet that as
soon as timu becomes more entrenched in
the U.S retail system that most of these
referral programs will be drastically
reduced here are the pros of buying from
temu there's cheap pricing T-Mobile
offers affordable pricing on a wide
range of products making it an excellent
choice for budget conscious Shoppers
it's also very easy to navigate the
teemu.com website has intuitive filters
and search options to help you find what
you need quickly there's also free
shipping Teemu offers free shipping on
almost all products saving you even more
money and the return process is hassle
free and straightforward and you also
get free return shipping on your first
return for every order within 90 days of
purchase they also have a huge catalog
they have millions of product listings
across 29 categories and 250
subcategories and they're constantly
giving out promotions Teemo offers
significant discounts and promotions and
right now they're running a free
shipping promotion on all orders of any
amount
here the downsides of buying from temu
the shipping times are slow customers
have reported that their orders took a
month to arrive the average shipping
time is 7 to 14 days on tmu the customer
service is also slow tmu's customer
support has a bad reputation for slow
response times and unhelpful
representatives the items are also
poorly packed customers have reported
receiving items that were damaged during
shipping due to inadequate protective
packaging and they're slow to give
refunds Teemu initiates a refund only
after they receive the return order
which can take anywhere between a week
to a month and then after that it takes
seven to Thirty Days for the refund to
be processed depending on your payment
method
so the million dollar question here is
should you be buying from temu Teemo is
a great option for people looking to buy
Goods directly from China suppliers at
dirt cheap prices however if you are
looking for products to sell on your own
online store or on Amazon consider more
reliable Brands and marketplaces such as
Alibaba Global Sources and made in China
unlike Alibaba Teemu doesn't have
wholesale suppliers that provide
additional discounts for larger
quantities in addition Teemu may not be
the best option if you're looking for
Specialized or hard to find items as
their catalog focuses more on General
products that said if you're looking for
a diverse range of affordable items and
you don't mind slightly longer shipping
times Teemu can be a great option for
you but just have the proper
expectations on product quality
now that you know more about Teemu make
sure you watch this video here about
their main competitor AliExpress